[ Watch on KissFlix.co ]
[Spring of The Blade]
[Episode 16]
I am more anxious.
I wish I could rewrite the past.
But the dead are gone,
and nothing can be changed.
I'm just a bit surprised why Lord Yan
seems more anxious than I am.
It's as if you wanted me to believe it immediately upon hearing,
and punish the murderer right after.
Isn't this
a bit hasty?
But this also reminds me...
Does the sudden appearance of this maidservant
involve any conspiracy behind the scenes?
What exactly is the intention?
Lord Yan,
if in my private residence,
I listen to a one-sided story,
set up a private court,
and catch the so-called murderer,
wouldn't that be the greatest contempt for the law and justice?
Wouldn't that be the greatest perversion of the law?
Lord Yan.
Lord Yan,
you want to redress the injustice for Qingyuan's birth mother.
Your sincerity is clear to heaven and earth.
Since that is the case,
we will certainly help you achieve this.
From tomorrow,
the Xie Residence will clarify the rumors about Fourth Madam,
and never let her suffer any grievance again.
However, the matter concerning Qingyuan's birth mother
happened many years ago.
It wouldn’t be appropriate to make a big deal out of it.
As for the real murderer back then,
we will certainly investigate it to the end.
I hope Lord Yan
can give us a few more days.
Is that possible?
Alright.
I believe Old Madam Xie
will do as she says.
[Xie Residence of Hengtang]
Your Lordship.
Mei Yinghua pushed all the blame
onto Chuntai.
Even with Cui'er as a witness,
as long as she refuses to admit it,
I won't be able to convict her before the Master
and Grandmother.
The path you chose for yourself is one
you should walk down with undivided resolve.
If there's any problem,
I will always have your back.
No matter when,
no matter what.
Ancestors of the Xie family, please protect me.
Protect me.
Protect us,
ancestors.
[Harmony Among Kin]
Second Madam.
The Bodhisattva will not protect
those with guilt in their hearts.
What are you doing here?
I came to ask,
since you keep saying
you never harmed my birth mother,
can you swear to it in front of the ancestors?
[Spirit Tablet of the Late Ancestors of the Xie Family]
Why should I listen to you?
Because Yan Rui listens to me.
Second Madam, you should know very well.
If Lord Yan insists on putting you in prison,
neither Father nor Grandmother
would hesitate to hand you over
for the Xie family's peace.
Do I look like I'm afraid of you?
Our Mei family also holds a noble title.
So what?
Even Father has to stay on Lord Yan's good side.
Can the mere Mei family save you?
No, let me put it this way.
Is a concubine's married daughter
worth being saved by the Mei family?
What do you want?
I want to hear you tell the truth.
If you swear to God
that you've never harmed my mother,
I will immediately have Yan Rui close this case.
But,
[Xie Clan Ancestral Hall]
if you break your vow,
your son, your pride and joy,
will be struck by lightning
and die a horrible death!
You just want me to swear.
Why involve my son Zhenglun?
What?
Are you afraid, Second Madam?
That's fine.
I'll go tell Yan Rui right now...
[Xie Clan Ancestral Hall]
I, Mei Yinghua, swear,
I'd never harmed Fourth Madam and Fifth Madam.
If I'm lying,
may my son Zhenglun be struck by lightning
and die a horrible death!
[Spirit Tablet of the Late Ancestors of the Xie Family]
[Xie Clan Ancestral Hall]
Zhenglun! Zhenglun!
Zhenglun!
Zhenglun, wake up!
A doctor.
Get a doctor quickly!
Why are you just standing there?
[Xie Clan Ancestral Hall]
Zhenglun!
Zhenglun...
This is karma.
He can't be saved.
Who was it that just swore a deadly vow?
Zhenglun!
Oh, God...
[Xie Clan Ancestral Hall]
It's all my fault.
Zhenglun!
I did it.
I did it all.
Please save my child.
Get a doctor to save my child.
I think
we need to give her
irrefutable proof.
[Xie Residence of Hengtang]
Qingyuan.
You wanted to see me?
Mother.
Qingyuan said you were guilty, but I didn't believe it.
I wanted to clear your name.
But why?
Why did you do such a vicious thing?
Son.
Qingyuan.
We have wronged you
and Fourth Madam.
You bitch!
[Xie Clan Ancestral Hall]
How dare you set me up!
Mother.
We can't keep making mistakes.
Father.
My mother has acknowledged her mistake.
Since things have come to this,
I will no longer defend her.
I only ask that she spend the rest of her life with the Xie family.
Father.
Zhenglun,
you may leave first.
Grandmother...
Be a good boy.
Go change your clothes.
Zhenglun.
♪ Waiting for a dream to sink into the depths of the night ♪
Mei Yinghua,
you framed my mother
♪ Waiting for a rain to wash away the heat burning in my eyes ♪
and made her bear a disgraceful name
so she'd leave the residence voluntarily.
♪ Waiting for a few flowers to bloom, then quietly fall ♪
You even wanted to drive us
both to our deaths.
♪ Only then do I understand right from what's wrong and bitter ♪
You really should
pay for my mother's life!
♪ Pear blossoms drift through the courtyard, fluttering like snowflakes in a song ♪
That's an accusation.
After Jin Chunqing left the Xie Residence,
♪ Singing the silence of love and hate ♪
I had no idea where she went.
How can you pin this on me?
♪ Which moment is hypothetical, and which is a real choice? ♪
♪ Who is drifting aimlessly in the wind? ♪
Whether you did it or not,
you know best in your heart.
♪ I wonder why joy is always so scarce in this world ♪
♪ I wonder, is that tear a loss or a gain? ♪
Qingyuan,
are you sure Concubine Mei killed her?
♪ Two souls trapped on the opposite banks of life and death ♪
Yes,
♪ May you and I overcome karma's bonds ♪
I'm sure.
9 years ago,
she started a fire at my house.
My mother
died in that fire.
Nonsense. I didn't kill anyone!
Master!
I believe
Fourth Lady and Cui'er are telling the truth.
You and Fourth Madam
were once deeply in love.
At this point,
do you still have the heart
to let her die with a grievance?
Please look into this, Master.
You bitch!
Mother! Mother!
-How dare you frame me! -Mother! Mother!
-Mother! Mother! -Enough!
[Harmony Among Kin]
I admit,
I resented Fifth Madam for being so favored
and overbearing.
So I poisoned her!
But I only gave her abortion pills.
I didn't want her dead!
I framed Fourth Madam
because I just wanted to drive her out of the residence.
I really didn't kill anyone.
I don't know what happened later.
All this talk about murder and arson
is pure nonsense!
[Harmony Among Kin]
Concubine Mei.
I only care about one thing.
You finally admitted it.
You poisoned her
with your own hands,
didn't you?
Master,
please believe me.
I didn't kill anyone.
Father.
It's been over a decade.
Even if you kill my mother now,
Fourth Madam and Fifth Madam won't come back to life.
Father,
please spare my mother.
Listen to me, everyone.
From today on,
[Harmony Among Kin]
Zhengjun
is no longer your mother.
Father!
Grandmother.
I beg of you.
Please help me persuade my father.
Okay?
I will take responsibility for Mother's crimes.
I will accept any beating or punishment.
I beg you, Grandmother.
Second Madam is your concubine.
You make the decision.
[Xie Clan Ancestral Hall]
Fifty Strokes of the Family Cane.
Whether she survives is up to fate.
Qingyuan
pays her respects to Grandmother
and Mother.
How is it?
How are things
over at Liuhua Courtyard?
To answer you, Mother,
Second Madam is still breathing.
Second Young Master pulled some strings.
They didn't beat her to death.
Amitabha.
Even so,
have the servants
send her back to Liuhua Courtyard first.
Pick an inconspicuous day later
and send her away to the farmstead.
This time,
the Xie Residence really owes you and your mother.
After some time,
we'll invite your mother's spirit tablet into the Xie Residence
and enshrine it in the ancestral hall.
I appreciate your kindness,
Grandmother.
But my mother was wrongly accused.
It might be inappropriate to enshrine her in the ancestral hall now.
Danyue Pavilion is my mother's former residence.
I'm used to living there too.
I hope you will allow me
to enshrine my mother's tablet in Danyue Pavilion.
It will be convenient for me to pay respects frequently.
Fine.
As you wish.
Thank you, Grandmother.
I know that
recently, the residence
has had much trouble because of me.
But as my mother's child,
how could I just sit back and watch
when my mother was wronged?
As for those who committed evil,
I
will definitely not let them off easily.
But I understand clearly,
and I'm deeply grateful
for the tolerance
that you and Mother
have shown me.
Since you have achieved your goal this time,
in the days to come,
I hope you can live peacefully
and not cause any more trouble.
Qingyuan,
the herbal shop business
will still be managed by you.
Just as the Old Madam said,
your birth mother's matter
has been settled as you wished.
Cultivate your character in the future
and treat others generously.
Remember that.
I will keep your teachings in mind.
Mother.
Mei Yinghua has confessed her crimes.
From now on,
no one in this world
[Memorial Tablet of Lady Jin, Concubine of Lord Xie]
will call you a murderous villain again.
No one
will ever hurt you like this again.
[Memorial Tablet of Lady Jin, Concubine of Lord Xie]
Father.
Qingyuan.
I am deeply ashamed of making you
and your mother suffer this injustice for so many years.
It's all in the past.
In the past,
you were kept
in the dark by Second Madam.
[Memorial Tablet of Lady Jin, Concubine of Lord Xie]
Chunqing.
Mother,
are you seeing this?
Father is here to see you.
[Danyue Pavilion]
Seeing Zhenglun today
reminds me of my younger self.
He was passionate and impulsive.
When I was young,
I wanted to pierce the sky.
But eventually,
I had to submit to my family name, my clan,
rules, and etiquette.
Qingyuan.
Concubine Mei
has paid the price for her actions.
Let it all be in the past.
From now on,
our family will live well.
I must make up for what I owe you.
Father.
Have you ever occasionally
thought of my birth mother?
Of course.
Not a day goes by without me thinking of her.
Mother is from a well-matched, prestigious family.
Marrying her
helped you advance in the court.
Second Madam is from a merchant family,
which can help
the Xie family's business.
Third Madam is from a scholarly family,
which can elevate
your reputation
among scholars.
My birth mother was of humble origins.
She had no prestigious background
and couldn't help the Xie family.
So why do you say that
she was the only wife
in your heart?
You don't understand.
[Danyue Pavilion]
Everything I do
is for this family.
Qingyuan.
You are still young.
When you reach my age,
perhaps you will understand.
Many things in life
are hard to balance.
I had to be the pillar of the Xie family
while not failing the woman I love.
It was hard.
To be the pillar of the Xie family,
everything must be for the sake of the family.
The firmer the foundation, the better.
The taller the tower, the better.
Even if it means sacrificing my own love
or even my life.
How can I care about anything else?
As for myself,
when have I ever had my own life?
Chunqing has passed away.
True love will never come by again.
I have failed your birth mother,
and I fear I can never make it up to her.
Qingyuan.
If your birth mother knew about this,
now,
she would only want one thing,
and that is for you to be well.
Do you understand?
Father.
I understand.
From now on,
I will be a good daughter
[Danyue Pavilion]
and won't make you suffer and feel guilty anymore.
You don't understand!
I don't want you to do those.
I only hope
you do one thing.
That is, from now on,
be safe, healthy,
and carefree.
Rest early.
You value the reputation of the Xie family so much.
For this reputation,
you didn't hesitate to kill my mother with your own hands.
Then I must topple this mountain
you built with your own hands
right in front of you.
What's wrong?
Aren't you happy
that I'm back?
Wei Changyan escaped.
I searched for hundreds of miles,
but still couldn't find him.
You don't need to worry about this.
Everything is under control.
The bait we threw out
might catch an even bigger fish.
I don't want any big fish!
I want Wei Changyan dead.
I want him to pay with his life
for the 72 deaths of our Shen family!
I promise you.
Wei Changyan
will only die by my hands.
And I won't let the people behind him and Xie Shu
off either.
Zhenglun.
Although your birth mother made a big mistake,
I know
you are a good child.
When you return to the Northern Frontier,
take good care of yourself.
Don't forget
to write home often.
Okay.
Grandmother.
Take care of yourself too.
Zhenglun.
Don't worry about things at home.
Do your job well.
Yes.
Mother.
[Guohuai Inn]
I'm leaving.
The family depends on you from now on.
Take on your responsibilities.
Don't act like a child
and waste your life away.
[Guohuai Inn]
Brother!
Take care!
Go back.
Brother!
Take care!
♪ Waiting for a dream to sink into the depths of the night ♪
♪ Waiting for a rain to wash away the heat burning in my eyes ♪
[Guohuai Inn]
♪ Waiting for a few flowers to bloom, then quietly fall ♪
♪ Only then do I understand right from what's wrong and bitter ♪
♪ Pear blossoms drift through the courtyard, fluttering like snowflakes in a song ♪
♪ Singing the silence of love and hate ♪
♪ Which moment is hypothetical, and which is a real choice? ♪
♪ Who is drifting aimlessly in the wind? ♪
♪ I wonder why joy is always so scarce in this world ♪
♪ I wonder, is that tear a loss or a gain? ♪
Even now, I still remember
how Mother sewed winter clothes for us back then.
♪ Two souls trapped on the opposite banks of life and death ♪
Although she was hot-tempered,
to Zhengjun and me,
♪ May you and I overcome karma's bonds ♪
she always gave her all.
I don't know
why she became like this.
Eldest Brother.
A person's faults do not extend to their children.
Mei Yinghua's actions have nothing to do with you.
I won't blame you.
Tomorrow,
I will head to the battlefield.
If this life
can atone for half of her sins,
it will be enough to repay our bond.
I also hope
it can lessen some of the
hatred in your heart.
Don't speak nonsense.
You will surely
protect the nation, achieve great things,
and return in triumph.
Qingyuan.
These are freshly dried persimmons from the Northern Frontier.
They are soft, sticky, and sweet.
I picked among three types
and chose the sweetest one.
Try it.
If you like it,
I'll dry a whole rack of them when I return,
just for us to eat.
Thank you, Eldest Brother.
I consider you my sister.
Naturally, I hope that
you can move on from your hatred soon.
At your blooming age,
you should smile more.
Eldest Brother,
I hope you return in triumph.
Your Majesty.
This ginseng is well-aged.
I have tested the temperature,
it's just right to drink.
Eunuch Xia, you are indeed used to
serving the late Emperor.
The late Emperor loved this soup,
but I do not.
The late Emperor relied on this soup for longevity.
But now,
Your Majesty is in your prime,
which is a blessing for the nation.
We old servants
all wish you good health.
Is there any news outside recently?
I wouldn't call it news,
but over in Hengtang,
public resentment is boiling over.
It's getting out of hand.
It's strange,
the honest censors usually
love to petition for the people.
But now, over in Hengtang,
they have
gone silent.
Since public resentment is boiling,
let Shen Run come back first.
♪ If the wind softly whispers your name ♪
♪ If my heart softly hears your voice ♪
♪ I'm still here, holding on to our memories ♪
♪ Quietly waiting in the passage of time for a reply ♪
♪ Listening to every word, every line, everything about you ♪
♪ Your gentle breath, the traces left by longing ♪
♪ No sight could ever compare to you, forever in my heart ♪
Smells good, Miss.
♪ My every joy and sorrow has become part of your journey ♪
What is this?
Poria and yam strengthen the spleen,
while gorgon nut, lotus seed, and ginseng nourish the body.
♪ A lifetime, devoted only to you ♪
It is perfect for those recovering from severe injuries or illnesses.
♪ Giving you all the love in my heart ♪
This product
might also sell very well.
♪ Our paths have never truly parted ♪
My Lady, you're so capable.
Whatever you do will succeed.
Fan Zhong said
Lord Yan would come over after finishing his government duties.
♪ If the wind softly whispers your name ♪
♪ If my heart softly hears your voice ♪
♪ I'm still here, holding on to our memories ♪
♪ Quietly waiting in the passage of time for a reply ♪
♪ Listening to every word, every line, everything about you ♪
My Lady,
it's already the third quarter of the You hour.
♪ Your gentle breath, the traces left by longing ♪
Throw this away.
Qingyuan!
Young Master.
Young Master Li.
Are you alright?
♪ No sight could ever compare to you, forever in my heart ♪
Thank you for your concern, Young Master Li.
Glad you're fine.
♪ My every joy and sorrow has become part of your journey ♪
They all said you were in trouble,
but I didn't believe it.
I was about to come looking for you,
but my father locked me up instead.
♪ A lifetime, devoted only to you ♪
Soon after, I heard
that you were fine.
But I really missed you,
♪ Giving you all the love in my heart ♪
so I went on a hunger strike for days
♪ Our paths have never truly parted ♪
before I finally got the chance to come out.
Sorry to make you worry.
I'm fine.
New pastries?
My Lady made it herself.
♪ No sight could ever compare to you, forever in my heart ♪
It's called Ningxin Cake.
♪ My every joy and sorrow has become part of your journey ♪
♪ A lifetime, devoted only to you ♪
Ningxin Cake?
♪ Giving you all the love in my heart ♪
Is it the 'xin' in Li Congxin?
♪ Our paths have never truly parted ♪
Good name.
It means to calm the mind and soothe the spirit.
It still suits me perfectly.
Miss, you invited me to taste the new pastries.
Why did you give it to someone else first?
Punctuality is a basic virtue of a gentleman.
Your Lordship was late yourself.
Won't you let those who arrived early eat first?
I came out of a pile of dead bodies.
I've never learned any ways of a gentleman.
Lord Yan, of course you're a gentleman.
Not only a gentleman,
but also a savior to my wife and me.
I'll take a seat first.
If he hadn't saved you,
I'd have left for the afterlife with you.
Then you can leave right now.
I'll give you this empty title.
A gentleman doesn't take what others love,
but I
like to take by force.
Qingyuan.
My mother has already prepared the betrothal gifts for me.
They will be sent to Xie Residence in a few days.
When the time comes, I hope Lord Yan
will do me the honor
of attending our wedding.
It's so crowded.
Young master.
The Marquis is back.
Let's go quickly.
Wasn't he supposed to entertain guests tonight?
Why did he come back early?
If you don't want to go back, that's fine.
I'll just get beaten again.
It's all up to you.
Qingyuan.
I have something to do today,
so I'll leave first.
The Ningxin Cake is delicious,
and I like the name very much.
I'll come again another day.
I will return the plate.
Keep it.
Childish.
Exactly.
I'm talking about you.
What a heartless shopkeeper.
I was late because I was queuing
for this osmanthus candy.
Not only did I get nothing in return,
but someone else reaped the benefits.
He even stole my Ningxin Cakes.
Then tell me, Your Lordship,
what kind of return do you want?
It's almost closing time.
Accompany me for a stroll.
How is Your Lordship's injury?
Without you by my side,
it's taking its time to heal.
Lately, the wound has been aching slightly.
My chest
even bled a little today.
Why is it so serious?
Let me see.
Now?
All right, come on.
Yan Rui!
Since you care so much about me,
I will cherish my life in the future
so as not to let you down.
You are so shameless.
You got hurt because of me.
That's why I asked.
Even if you fatally injure yourself in the future,
I won't care.
Of course.
You're engaged now.
Naturally, you can't be entangled with a notorious
corrupt official.
In the future,
even if I go through hell for you,
you won't feel sorry for me.
Do you have to speak like this?
Not necessarily.
I won't say it anymore.
Tell me,
after Yan and Yunya
leave Anxiang Village,
what kind of story will they experience?
Yan would bask in the sun
and drink every day.
As for Yunya,
in these spring-like days,
she can finally get rid of the burdens on her shoulders
and live the way she wants.
Let's go.
I'll take you somewhere.
So this is the wish-granting tree
you mentioned?